You might have heard of the expression 'a guilty pleasure' – maybe it's the chocolate bar you buy on the way home from work, or the new clothes that you don't really need.
你可能听说过"内疚的快乐"这个说法——也许是你下班路上买的巧克力棒，或者你并不真正需要的新衣服。
It comes from the idea that when we treat ourselves, it can sometimes leave us feeling guilty.
这源于这样一种想法：当我们犒劳自己时，有时会让我们感到内疚。
Perhaps we don't feel we deserved it, or we don't think it was a responsible way to spend our money.
也许我们觉得自己不值得，或者认为这不是一种负责任的花钱方式。
But should we feel like this?
但我们该有这种感觉吗？
Do we really have to feel guilty about treating ourselves?
犒劳自己真的需要感到内疚吗？
Perhaps not.
也许不必。
Psychologists have suggested that buying things for yourself can make you feel better as it provides an opportunity to take control of your situation.
心理学家指出，为自己购物可以让你感觉更好，因为它提供了一个掌控自己处境的机会。
It can give you social contact as well as a confidence boost from changes you make to your self-image.
它能带来社交联系，也能通过改变自我形象来增强自信。
It may be that as well as lifting your mood, when you buy a treat, you might just be looking after yourself.
当你付钱犒劳自己时，除了改善心情，你可能只是在照顾你自己。
Of course, there are also examples of people turning to destructive behaviour when faced with stressful circumstances.
当然，也有人们在面临压力环境时转向破坏性行为的例子。
People might spend money that they don't have or turn to dangerous addictions.
人们可能会花自己还没有的钱，或者陷入危险的成瘾行为。
Psychologist Leon Seltzer considers the difference between self-indulgence and self-nurturing.
心理学家莱昂·塞尔策思考了自我放纵与自我养育之间的区别。
Self-indulgence can be reckless and have negative consequences, while self-nurturing is taking responsible decisions to satisfy our needs and take care of ourselves in ways that don't have a significant impact.
自我放纵可能是鲁莽的，并带来负面后果，而自我养育则是做出负责任的决策，以满足我们的需求，并以不会产生重大影响的方式照顾自己。
One stress that people may need to deal with is exam stress.
人们需要应对的一种压力是考试压力。
Many universities publish guides with advice for coping with exam stress.
许多大学发布了关于应对考试压力的指南。
Reflecting the difference between self-indulgence and self-nurture, they recommend rewarding yourself for your efforts, doing things that you enjoy and are good at so that you can feel accomplishment and to avoid things that may make you feel worse afterwards.
这些指南反映了自我放纵与自我养育之间的区别，建议奖励自己的努力，做自己享受且擅长的事情，以便感受到成就感，并避免那些之后可能会让你感觉更糟的事情。
So perhaps, as long as we make responsible decisions, we shouldn't feel guilty about our guilty pleasures.
所以，也许只要我们做出负责任的决定，就不必为我们的"内疚的快乐"感到内疚。